edumedia-sciences.com 2019-11-15

# Privacy Policy – eduMedia

_Last updated: December 4, 2018_

Your privacy is important to us.

For the purposes of this document, the terms below are defined as follows:

  *  **eduMedia** : Company registered at the RCS of Bordeaux (France), which offers online services in the form of a bank of educational resources and a number of services dedicated to learning. « eduMedia » is a registered trademark.
  *  **Site** : The websites www.edumedia-sciences.com and / or junior.edumedia-sciences.com
  *  **School:** A public or private building that welcomes students for instruction.
  *  **You** or **the user** : A person who uses **eduMedia** 's online services through the **Site**.
  *  **Subscription:** A binding contract between **the user** and the **eduMedia** company for use of the **Site** over a given period of time.
  *  **eduMedia resource(s)** : Digital resources (animations, simulations, quizzes and videos) accessible from the **Site**.

##  **Personal information**

You can generally use the **Site** and the **eduMedia Resources** without disclosing any personal information. However, **You** may not be able to take advantage of some of the features and services if **You** refuse to provide certain information about yourself:  For a _Teacher_ **Subscription,** the subscriber must provide the following personal information:

  * First and last names
  * Email address
  * Name of the school 

To create a personal _Teacher's Area_ , the subscriber must provide the following personal information:

  * First and last names
  * Email address
  * Name of the school

To subscribe to our newsletter, the user must provide an email address.

##  **Purposes of processing personal information**

The above information is essential for the proper operation of your **Subscriptions** and related services.  **You** can modify or delete your information any time by contacting us through our online contact form or by mailing a request to **eduMedia’s** head office at 8 Rue Borie, 33300 Bordeaux, France.  
We may then ask for proof of identity to verify the legitimacy of your request.

WARNING: If you delete your account, all corresponding accounts will also be deleted, preventing access to the content. Such an irreversible decision may impact other users.

##  **Identity of the personal data controller**

 **eduMedia** is the only recipient of this personal information. The sole purpose of processing this information is to provide **You** with secure, quality access and to contact **You** if there is any abnormal use of your account or to update one of our services.  
Please note that the economic model of **eduMedia** does not rely on advertising or the sale or exchange of customer data.

##  **How long personal data is kept**

 **eduMedia** keeps the data required for the proper operation of your account.  **You** have a permanent right of access to your profile and the personal data contained in it, with the option of modifying or deleting the information upon request through the online contact form.

###  _Your contributions_

A _School_ or _Teacher_ subscription comes with a capture service that lets **you** create your own resources. These resources are hosted by **eduMedia**.  **You** have a permanent right of access to your video captures with the option of removing them from our servers in your _Teacher's Area._  
Personal data related to your accounts or contributions will be destroyed after your account has been inactive for more than two years or immediately following a request from you.

##  **Cookies**

 **eduMedia** uses 3 types of cookies, which are required for the proper operation of the **Site** :

  * Session cookies: temporary files from the **Site** that have a 24-hour lifespan. These cookies store a unique session ID and allow the **User** to memorize connection information without having to re-enter identifiers on each of the **Site** 's pages. These cookies do not store any personal information and are not used for profiling or tracking the **User**.
  * Customization cookies: cookies deposited by JavaScript code from the **Site,** whose lifespan expires once the browser is closed. These cookies are used to memorize **User** preferences.

  * Third party cookies from the sites listed below: 
    1.  _Google Analytics_ : service that measures the **Site** 's audience.   
This service has been set to make the data sent to Google Analytics anonymous. More information about the data collected by this service is available at the following URL: _[https://privacy.google.com/businesses/](https://privacy.google.com/businesses/%C2%A0)_  
    2.  _Typekit_ : service for accessing a font library to standardize the presentation of our content according to computer systems.  
The information collected by Typekit is available at the following URL: _<https://www.adobe.com/be_fr/privacy/policies/typekit.html>_
    3. _AddThis_ : service that lets you share an **EduMedia Resource** on social networks. More information about the data collected by this service is available at the following URL: <https://www.addthis.com/privacy>

## **Modifications**

This document about personal data may be subject to change in accordance with an eventual evolution of the **eduMedia** online service.  
These changes may occur at any time without notice. The **User** is also invited to consult this document regularly. If it is modified, **Subscribers** will receive an alert in the form of an email or pop-up on our **Site.**

If these new conditions seem unacceptable to **you** , please stop using the **Site.** Subscribers may claim a refund calculated in proportion to the period of use.

The most recent date of modification of the present Privacy Policy is indicated at the top of the page
